Guide to the Committee to Frame a World Constitution Records 1945-1951
University of Chicago Library
Committee to Frame a World Constitution. Records
1945-1951
19 linear feet (38 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Committee to Frame a World Constitution was first convened in the fall of 1945 as part of the post-World War II World Federalist movement. The Records contain correspondence and miscellaneous material reflecting the close relations between the Committee and other organizations advocating some form of world government. The papers are comprised of the files of the Committee secretariat, which was also the editorial staff for the journal Common Cause.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
After a Round Table Discussion on 12 August 1945, in the course of which University of Chicago Chancellor Hutchins emphasized the need for world government, Richard P. McKeon and G. A. Borgese wrote to the Chancellor asking him for financial and moral support for an institute to formulate a world constitution. On 16 September 1945. Hutchins gave his support and by November 1945 the first document was presented for consideration by the Committee. In 1947 The Preliminary Draft of a World Constitution (Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1948) was published. From June 1947 through June 1951 the Committee published a journal, Common Cause, devoted to articles concerned with problems relevant to the issue of world government and how to affect it.
The members of the Committee at the time of the publication of the Draft were: Robert M. Hutchins, G. A. Borgese, Mortimer J. Adler, Stringfellow Barr, Albert Guérard, Harold A. Innis, Erich Kahler, Wilber G. Katz, Charles H. McIlwain, Robert Redfield, and Rexford G. Tugwell. Additionally, Elisabeth Mann Borgese worked as a research assistant for the Committee and later editor of the journal Common Cause.
Scope Note
The Committee to Frame a World Constitution Records contains correspondence and miscellaneous material. This collection reflects the close relations between the Committee and other organizations advocating some form of world government. Specifically, the papers are comprised of the files of the Committee secretariat, which was also the editorial staff for Common Cause. They include the 150 documents used as the basis for the discussions in the thirteen meetings of the Committee; the stenographic transcriptions of the meetings; a complete set of Common Cause and a single copy of The Draft. The Records also include correspondence concerning Committee administrative matters, publication, and business arrangements, comments on Common Cause and the preliminary draft of the Constitution, and miscellaneous manuscript materials.
The Committee to Frame a World Constitution Records are divided into six series.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Adler, Mortimer Jerome, 1902-; Barr, Stringfellow, 1897-; Borgese, Elisabeth Mann; Borgese, Giuseppe Antonio, 1882-1952; Cousins, Norman; Cranston, Alan MacGregor; Guérard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph), 1914-; Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1899-; McKeon, Richard Peter, 1900-; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955; Mayer, Milton Sanford, 1908-; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-; Nef, John Ulric, 1899-; Redfield, Robert, 1897-; Tugwell, Rexford G. (Rexford Guy), 1891-; Wright, Quincy, 1890-1970; Committee to Frame a World Constitution; World Association of World Federalists; International organization; World politics
INVENTORY
- Series I: Administrative and Financial Papers
  This series includes inter-office memoranda to the Committee staff; inter-University memoranda concerning housekeeping matters; some subscription matters; correspondence with authors concerning copies of articles; intra-Committee correspondence; magazine exchange arrangements; and correspondence relating to lay-out and publication of Common Cause. (This material is often supplemented in Series II, Correspondence.)
  - "A" Administration, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "B" Administration, 1944-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Budget, July 1948--June 1949, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Business, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "C" Administration, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Central Administration (Inter-office memoranda), 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Copyright, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "F" Administration, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "H" Administration, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "K" Administration, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "L" Administration, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Office-Expenditures, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Office-Expenditures, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Office-Requisitions and Receipts, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Office-Personnel (Letters requesting positions; personnel records of employees), 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Office-Personnel (Letters requesting positions; personnel records of employees), 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Office-Personnel (Correspondence relating to personnel), 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Office-Personnel (Memoranda to employees of Committee; Phoenix Correspondence, November-December 1947), 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "P" Administration, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "S" Administration, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Accounts, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series II: Correspondence
  This series consists of the correspondence to Common Cause requesting copies, information, and subscriptions; correspondence with authors; concerning dissemination of the journal; personal-official letters with various leaders and organizations in the World Federation Movement; business arrangements of the Committee and its Journal with other organizations; publishing and printing matters; letters of transmittal of Preliminary Draft and copies of Journal; a few letters including individual plans for world government. This material is arranged alphabetically and in the order in which it was received from the Committee.
  - "A" General Correspondence (old), 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Aa-Ak General Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A-Az General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Advertising and Sales, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Advertisements (From c. June 1950), 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Advertisements, Common Cause (To c. June 1950), 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Altrocchi, Rudolph, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - All Members (Correspondence to), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "B" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "B" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ba-Bh General Correspondence, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bi-Bz General Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Baldanzi, George, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Barr, Stringfellow, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bellanca, August, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Benitez, Jaime, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography: World Government, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Biography: Common Cause, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Harrison, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brünning, Heinrich, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "C" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "C" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ca-Ci General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ck-Cz General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Common Cause, Vol. 1, No. 9 (March 1948), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Common Cause, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Exchange Publication, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Common Cause (Magazine Exchanges), 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Common Cause (Letters on expiration), 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Constitution, Preliminary Draft (Amendments to), 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Constitutional Conventions, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cranston, Alan, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "D" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "D" General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Davis, Garry, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Distributors of Common Cause, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Distributors of Common Cause (Foreign Agencies), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Documents, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Dunham, Vera Sandomirsky, 1946-1951 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Duke University Cooperative Project, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "E" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "E General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "F" General Correspondence (old), 1947-1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "F" General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Faculty News Bulletin, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Farmer Fyke, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Federalist Press, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Foundation Book, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fund Raising, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "G" General Correspondence (old), 1947-1949 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "G" General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Goethe Bicentennial, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Guérard, Albert (old), 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Guérard, Albert (new), 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "H" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ha-Hm General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hn-Hz General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hansson, Johan, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hart, Hornell, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hotels, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "I" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "I" General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Inagaki, Morikatsu, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ingalls, Jeremy, 1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Information Letters (concerning Common Cause or the Committee), 1950 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Inquiries and Contributions, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "J" General Correspondence (old), 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "J" General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Japan, World Federal Government, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ka General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ke-Ku General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ka-Kl General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Km-Kz General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "L" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "L" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - La-Lh General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Li-Lz General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Lang, Reginald D., 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Library, the Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Library of International Relations, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Mc" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1949 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Mc" General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - McIlwain, Charles, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - McCormick, Ada P. "Letter" Magazine, 1947-1951 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - McKeon, Richard P., 1945-1950 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "M" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "M" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Ma-Me General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Mf-Mz General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Mann, Thomas, 1947-1950 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Marzullo, Sal Gene, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Mayer, Milton, 1946-1950 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Meyer, Cord, 1946-1951 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, Common Cause, 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, General Correspondence (1Dec. 1948-14 Sept. 1949) I, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, General Correspondence (1 Dec. 1948-14 Sept. 1949) II, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Momdadori, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1947-1951 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "N" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1949 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "N" General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Nagel, Louis-Editions, 1948-1951 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Nation, The, 1946-1951 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Nef, John U, 1946-1951 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "O" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - "O" General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Office, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Office Memoranda, 1946-1950 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ogilvy, Stewart, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Oliver, Stauffer, 1947-1951 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Orders, for Pamphlets, etc., 1946-1949 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Orders for Documents, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "P" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "P" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Pa-Pe General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Pf-Pz General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Parallel Organization, National Peace Council (London), 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Parallel Organization, Students for Federal World Government (Student Federalists), 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Parallel Organization, The United World Federalists, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Parallel Organization, Wereld Federalisten Beweging Nederland, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Parallel Organization, Miscellaneous-Declarations, etc., 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Peck, George T., 1946-1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pocono Conference, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Poole Brothers, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Posin, D. Q., 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Publicity Material, N.B. Press, University of Chicago: SEE University of Chicago Press, 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "R" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1949 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "R" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1949 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "R" General Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Railway Express, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Rawnsley, 1947-1950 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Redfield, Robert, 1946-1951 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Round Table, 1946-1950 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Ruopp, Phillip, 1947-1949 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - "S" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "S" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sa-Sk General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Sl-Sz General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Subscriptions: Periodicals (General); General Material and Subscriptions to Magazines, 1948-1951 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Sohn, Louis B., 1948-1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "T" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - "T" General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Taylor, Glen H., 1946-1950 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Tchou, Thomas, 1948-1951 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Tugwell, R. G., 1946-1951 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "U" General Correspondence (old), 1947-1949 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "U" General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - U.N.E.S.C.O., 1947-1950 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - University, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1947-1951 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Usborne, Henry, 1947-1951 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "V" General Correspondence (old), 1945-1949 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "V" General Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "W" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "W" General Correspondence (old), 1946-1949 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Wa-Wel General Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Wer-Wk General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Wl-Wz General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Wofford, Harris and Clare, 1948-1951 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - World Federation, 1945-1949 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - World Government News, 1948-1951 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Wright, Quincy, 1948-1950 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Wynner, Edith, 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - X,Y,Z, and Unidentified General Correspondence, 1946-1951 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Series III: Common Cause and the Preliminary Draft Files
  This series includes letters to the Committee and the Journal commenting upon the Draft Constitution and/or the Journal of the Committee, Common Cause, and its articles. Many of the letters are from correspondents who have plans of their own and are bringing them to the attention of the Committee and the Journal.
  - Comments on Common Cause, General, 1948-1951 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Comments on Preliminary Draft, 1947-1949 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Preliminary Draft, Outlines, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary Draft, Revision, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Preliminary Draft of a World Constitution, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Committee to Frame a World Constitution, Preliminary Draft of a World Constitution, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Errata to Preliminary Draft of a World Constitution, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Common Cause, Vol. 1, no. 9, "Preliminary Draft of a World Constitution," 1948 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Common Cause, Volume 1, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Common Cause, Volume 2, 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Common Cause, Volume 3, 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Common Cause, Volume 4, 1950-1951 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - A-F, 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - G-M, 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - N-Z, 1946-1949 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - A, 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - B, 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - C, 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - D, 1947-1950 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - E, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - F, 1947-1949 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - G, 1947-1949 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - H, 1947-1950 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - I-J, 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - K, 1947-1951 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - L, 1947-1951 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - M, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - N, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - O-P, 1947-1951 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Q-R, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - S, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - T, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - U-V, 1947-1950 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - W, 1947-1949 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - X-Z, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Manuscript Material
  This series consists of manuscript copies of articles appearing in the Journal, lectures, and speeches by men prominent or connected with the Committee or the Journal relevant to the World Federation Movement, e.g., Borgese, Hutchins, Quincy Wright, and others. The series also includes typescript, holograph, and mimeographed copies of the documents issued by the Committee in the Document Series 1-150.
  - Borgese, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Borgese, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Adler-Guerard, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Holt-Jackson, 1946-1951 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Joyce-Odne, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Papanek-Teller, 1948-1951 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Tugwell, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Usborne-Wood-Unsigned, 1946-1950 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proof, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts, Reports, Briefs, 1947-1949 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Proposals for amendment of the United Nations Charter, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Original and unmimeographed copies of Documents 1-9, 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Document 7, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Original and unmimeographed copies of Documents 10-28, 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Original and unmimeographed copies of Documents 29-53, 1945-1946 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Original copies of Documents 54-74, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Original copies of Documents 75-95, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Original copies of Documents 96-110, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Original copies of Document 111, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Document 111, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Original copies of Documents 112-113, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Draft II-Third Edition (Original), 1946 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Draft II, Third Revised Edition, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Draft V, Revised Edition, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Document 113, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Original copies of Document 114, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Original Documents 128-134, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Original Documents 135-140, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Original Document 141, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Drafts of the Constitution, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Drafts of the Constitution, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Original Manuscript of Document 127, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Document 147, Constitutional Drafts basis for Document 147, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Document 147, Constitutional Drafts basis for Document 147, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Original copies of Document 148 and 149, includes detailed comment upon various segments of the Constitution by individuals whose opinions had been solicited, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- Series V: Documents
  This series is made up of mimeographed copies of Committee Documents 1--150. These documents consist of the original proposals and plans for the Committee, and the various papers submitted by its members to be used as a basis for discussion and the eventual formation of a Preliminary Draft Constitution.
  - Index of Documents, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Index and Documents 1-15, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Documents 16-36, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Documents 37-52, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Documents 53-70, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Documents 71-86, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Documents 87-101, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Documents 102-111, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Documents 112-125, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Documents 126-140 (Documents 122, 129, 133 missing), 1947 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Documents 141-148 (Document 145 missing), 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Documents 149-150, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Documents 1-33, 1945-1946 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Documents 34-74, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Documents 75-93, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Documents 94-99, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Documents 100-110, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Documents 111-113, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Documents 114-128, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Documents 130-144, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Documents 146-150, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Unnumbered Document, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified Pages, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Meeting Minutes
  This series includes the stenographic transcripts of the Committee Meetings, mimeographed.
  - Proceedings, New York, 17-18 Dec., 1945 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 4-5 Feb., Revised, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 4-5 Feb., Typewritten Copy, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings, New York, 29-30 March, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 15-16 April, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings, New York, 17-18 May, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 18-19 June, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings, New York, 19-20 July, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings, New York, 16-17 August, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 24-25 Oct., 1946 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 6 Feb., 1947 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 7 Feb., 1947 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 31 March, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 1 April, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 2 April, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 14 July, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 15 July, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings, New York, 17 Dec., 1945 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings, New York, 18 Dec., 1945 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 4-5 Feb., 1946 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings, New York, 29-30 March, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings, Chicago, 31 March, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 4)